Michael Longley papers, 1960-2000
Emory University
- Belfast Group sheets, Series 8; Box 60
  - Longley, Michael: "In Memoriam," "Christopher at Birth," "Freeze-Up," Saint Francis to the Birds," "Elegy for Fats Waller," Epitathalamion," "En Route" [with holograph corrections] (Box 60, Folder 17)
  - Longley, Michael: "Gathering Mushrooms," "To Bix Beiderbecke," "Nausicaa," "The Freemartin," "Narcissus," "Dr. Johnson Dying," In a Convent Cemetery," "Remembrance Day" (Box 60, Folder 18)
  - Longley, Michael: "To the Poets," "Mountain Swim," "A Nativity," "Miscarriage," "The North," "Lares," "Caravan" [2 copies, 1 with holograph corrections] (Box 60, Folder 19)
  - McGurk, Tom, December 1, [1965?] group meeting: "The Magi," "A.D. 1969," "A Tribute to Patrick Kavanagh," "Going Up" [part missing] (Box 60, Folder 20)
  - McGurk, Tom: "First-Born," "Kavanagh's Arrival," "Heartman - still beating strong!," "Big Ned," "A Parable of Stoney Ground," "Myxomatosis 1955," "The Empty Pages," and "Henry IX" (Box 60, Folder 21)
  - Mahon, Derek" "Poem in Belfast," "In Carrowdore Churchyard," "My Wicked Uncle," Canadian Pacific," "Famous Last Words," "As God Is My Judge," "The Poets Lie Where They Fell" (Box 60, Folder 22)
  - Muldoon, Paul: "Wind and Tree," "Hedges in Winter," "Cuckoo Corn" "Siesta," "Vampire," "Grass Widow," "The Indians on Alcatraz," and "The Electric Orchard" (Box 60, Folder 23)
  - Muldoon, Paul: "Stillborn," "Snail," "January," "Poem at Eighteen," "Hawk," "Hedgehog," Seanchas," "Unborn," "Leaving the Island" (Box 60, Folder 24)
  - Terry, Arthur: "A Small War," "The Appointment," "The Sisters," "Told After Breughel," and "Caesar" [with holograph correction] (Box 60, Folder 25)
  - Terry, Arthur: "Beginnings," Untitled ["On Sunday evenings in the poor quarter"], "Time Was," and "My Skeleton" [2 copies] (Box 60, Folder 26)
  - Terry, Arthur: "By Natural Piety" (Box 60, Folder 27)
  - Possible group sheets (Box 60, Folder 28)
- Arts Council of Northern Ireland records, 1969-1991, Series 9; Boxes 61-74; OP14
  Michael Longley worked for the Arts Council of Northern Ireland (ACNI) from 1970 - 1991. Initially employed as temporary Exhibitions Officer, he quickly became director of Traditional Arts; in 1982 he became Combined Arts Director, a position from which he oversaw Traditional Arts, Young Arts and Community Arts. Throughout his career with the Arts Council he was particularly interested in encouraging literature in Northern Ireland, although as his autobiographical essay "Blackthorn & Bonsai" shows, he often did so in the face of much resistance from the Council. Towards the end of his tenure with ACNI he also became a founder member of the Cultural Traditions Group, an organization which attempted to celebrate the diverse traditions of the Irish arts scene. This series contains correspondence and printed material relating to all of these matters. Particularly notable here is correspondence from numerous publishing organizations, including publishing houses and "little" magazines, showing the burgeoning of literary output during the 1970s and 1980s in Ireland.
  Subseries 9.1 contains materials collected by Michael Longley in connection with the Arts Council of Northern Ireland (ACNI). These materials pertain to the Council as a whole, as distinct from a particular department. It includes reports made by Longley to the Council, as well as various Council minutes, reports, agendas and new releases.
  Subseries 9.2 features various types of materials pertaining to specific ACNI Projects in the areas of Literature, Traditional Arts, Community Arts, and Young Arts. The correspondence subseries (9.3) has been divided into two main categories: correspondence regarding literary subjects, and correspondence regarding traditional Irish arts and community. The Literature category has been further divided into subcategories based on correspondent: correspondence with magazines and journals, presses, organizations, educational institutions, libraries, theatres and individuals. Arts Council publications, newspaper clippings, and other various printed material comprise Subseries 9.4.
  During his tenure as an Arts Council director, Michael Longley also became a member of the Cultural Traditions Group, which was established in 1988. A branch of Northern Ireland's Community Relations Council, the Cultural Traditions Group promoted traditional Irish culture and art-much like ACNI's Traditional Arts department. Subseries 9.5 features materials that relate to the Cultural Traditions Group: correspondence, minutes, and printed material. [Note: Cultural Traditions Group has since been renamed "Cultural Diversity Programme."]
  Organized into five subseries: (9.1) General Arts Council materials, (9.2) Arts Council projects, (9.3) Correspondence, (9.4) Printed material, and (9.5) Cultural Traditions Group materials.
  - General Arts Council materials, 1972-1991, Subseries 9.1; Box 61-62
    - Descriptions of ACNI Departments and Positions (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - Michael Longley's Code Key for materials received by ACNI (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - ACNI report by Michael Longley: "The Arts Council and the Libraries" (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - ACNI report by Michael Longley: "Literature and the Community" (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - ACNI report by Michael Longley: "A Paper on Publishing" (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - ACNI report by Michael Longley: "Paul Clarke-An Appreciation" (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - ACNI report by Michael Longley: "Review of Arts Funding Arrangements" (Box 61, Folder 7)
    - ACNI report by Michael Longley: untitled [upon appointment to Traditional Arts] (Box 61, Folder 8)
    - ACNI report by Michael Longley: "Writers in Residence" (Box 61, Folder 9)
    - ACNI minutes, reports and agendas: 1972 - 1978 (Box 61, Folder 10)
    - ACNI minutes, reports and agendas: 1979 - 1982 (Box 61, Folder 11)
    - ACNI minutes, reports and agendas: 1983 - 1984 (Box 61, Folder 12)
    - ACNI minutes, reports and agendas: 1985 - 1986 (Box 61, Folder 13)
    - ACNI minutes, reports and agendas: 1987 (Box 61, Folder 14)
    - ACNI minutes, reports and agendas: 1988 (Box 61, Folder 15)
    - ACNI minutes, reports and agendas: 1989 (Box 61, Folder 16)
    - ACNI minutes, reports and agendas: 1990 - 1991 (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - ACNI minutes, reports and agendas: undated (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - ACNI minutes, reports and agendas: drafts (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - ACNI memos: 1974 - 1979 (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - ACNI memos: 1980 - 1982 (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - ACNI memos: 1983 - 1987 (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - ACNI memos: 1988 - 1989 (Box 62, Folder 7)
    - ACNI memos: 1991 (Box 62, Folder 8)
    - ACNI memos: 1990 (Box 62, Folder 9)
    - ACNI memos: undated (Box 62, Folder 10)
    - ACNI News Releases: 1974 - 1991 (Box 62, Folder 11)
    - ACNI Personnel Files: Frank Murphy Debate (Box 62, Folder 12)
    - ACNI Personnel Files: Kent Dur Russel Hearing (Box 62, Folder 13)
    - ACNI Personnel Files: Noirin McKinney vs. ACNI (Box 62, Folder 14)
    - ACNI Personnel Files: Michael Haynes Situation (Box 62, Folder 15)
    - ACNI Report: Grants to Publishers in Northern Ireland (Box 62, Folder 16)
    - ACNI: Miscellaneous (Box 62, Folder 17)
  - Arts Council projects, circa 1970-1999, Subseries 9.2; Box 63; OP14
    - "At Home to the Honourable" (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Beck's Bier Bursary, 1990 (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - "In Their Element" [S. Heaney and D. Mahon tour] (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - "Life-Span": correspondence, July 1970 - October 1971 (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - "Life-Span": correspondence, November1971 - March 1972 (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - "Life-Span": correspondence, April - December - 1972 (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - "Life-Span": Press cuttings (Box 63, Folder 7)
    - "Life-Span": Programs, etc. (Box 63, Folder 8)
    - "Life-Span": Logo templates (Box 63, Folder 9)
    - "Life-Span": Financial documents (Box 63, Folder 10)
    - "Life-Span": Miscellaneous (Box 63, Folder 11)
    - Mick Marley's Carousel (Box 63, Folder 12)
    - The Poets' House - correspondence (Box 63, Folder 13)
    - The Poets' House - miscellaneous (Box 63, Folder 14)
    - "Room to Rhyme" [poetry tour] (Box 63, Folder 15)
    - "Room to Rhyme" poster (Box OP14)
    - "Take It Away" [poetry and jazz event] (Box 63, Folder 16)
    - "Two Evenings of Traditional Irish Music" (Box 63, Folder 17)
    - "You and Yours" [traditional Irish music] correspondence (Box 63, Folder 18)
    - "You and Yours" miscellaneous (Box 63, Folder 19)
    - Young Arts Program (Box 63, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1969-1991, Subseries 9.3; Box 64-72
    - Literature
    - Magazines and Journals: Audio Arts (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - Magazines and Journals: Belfast Review / Review (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - Magazines and Journals: Extro (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - Magazines and Journals: Fortnight [includes Fortnight Educational Trust correspondence] (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - Magazines and Journals: Gown Literary Supplement and Gown Independant Newspaper (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - Magazines and Journals: Honest Ulsterman (Box 64, Folder 6)
    - Magazines and Journals: North (Box 64, Folder 7)
    - Magazines and Journals: Poetry Ireland (Box 64, Folder 8)
    - Magazines and Journals: Theatre Ireland (Box 64, Folder 9)
    - Magazines and Journals: 2 Plus 2 (Box 64, Folder 10)
    - Magazines and Journals: Other publications: 1974-1984 (Box 64, Folder 11)
    - Magazines and Journals: Other publications: 1985-1989 (Box 64, Folder 12)
    - Magazines and Journals: Other publications: 1990-1991 (Box 64, Folder 13)
    - Magazines and Journals: Other publications: undated (Box 64, Folder 14)
    - Presses: Albertine Kennedy Publishing (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - Presses: Appletree Press (Box 65, Folder 2)
    - Presses: Beaver Row Press (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - Presses: Blackstaff Press: 1977-1978 (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - Presses: Blackstaff Press: 1979 (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - Presses: Blackstaff Press: 1980 (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - Presses: Blackstaff Press: 1981 (Box 65, Folder 7)
    - Presses: Blackstaff Press: 1982 (Box 65, Folder 8)
    - Presses: Blackstaff Press: 1983 (Box 65, Folder 9)
    - Presses: Blackstaff Press: 1984 (Box 65, Folder 10)
    - Presses: Blackstaff Press: 1985-1988 (Box 65, Folder 11)
    - Presses: Blackstaff Press: 1989 (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - Presses: Blackstaff Press: 1990 (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Presses: Blackstaff Press: 1991 (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - Presses: Blackstaff Press: Miscellaneous (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - Presses: Bloodaxe Books (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - Presses: Brandon Book Publishers Ltd. (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - Presses: Books Ireland (Box 66, Folder 7)
    - Presses: Chatto & Windus Ltd. (Box 66, Folder 8)
    - Presses: Faber & Faber Ltd. (Box 66, Folder 9)
    - Presses: Friar's Bush Press (Box 66, Folder 10)
    - Presses: The Gallery Press (Box 66, Folder 11)
    - Presses: Impact Printing Ltd. (Box 66, Folder 12)
    - Presses: The Lilliput Press Ltd. (Box 66, Folder 13)
    - Presses: North-West Books (Box 66, Folder 14)
    - Presses: The O'Brien Press (Box 66, Folder 15)
    - Presses: Ogmios Press (Box 66, Folder 16)
    - Presses: Poolbeg Press Ltd. (Box 66, Folder 17)
    - Presses: Pretani Press (Box 66, Folder 18)
    - Presses: Salmon Publishing (Box 66, Folder 19)
    - Presses: Wolfhound Press (Box 66, Folder 20)
    - Presses: other correspondence: 1976-1984 (Box 66, Folder 21)
    - Presses: other correspondence: 1985-1991 (Box 66, Folder 22)
    - Presses: Association of Little Presses Newsletters (Box 66, Folder 23)
    - Organizations: Ards Arts Centre (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Organizations: Armagh Diocesan Historical Society (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - Organizations: The Arts Council [Dublin]: 1974-1987 (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - Organizations: The Arts Council [Dublin]: 1988-1991 (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - Organizations: Arts Council of Great Britain (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - Organizations: Arvon Foundation Ltd. (Box 67, Folder 6)
    - Organizations: British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC) (Box 67, Folder 7)
    - Organizations: The British Council: 1973-1987 (Box 67, Folder 8)
    - Organizations: The British Council: 1988-1991 (Box 67, Folder 9)
    - Organizations: The British Council: Literature Advisory Committee Minutes (Box 67, Folder 10)
    - Organizations: The British Council: Miscellaneous (Box 67, Folder 11)
    - Organizations: Comóradh Énrí Uí Mhuirgheasa (Box 67, Folder 12)
    - Organizations: Department of Education [Bangor Co. Down] (Box 67, Folder 13)
    - Organizations: Department of Foreign Affairs [Dublin] (Box 67, Folder 14)
    - Organizations: Giros Poetry Collective (Box 67, Folder 15)
    - Organizations: Institute of Contemporary Arts Ltd. [London] (Box 67, Folder 16)
    - Organizations: Irish P.E.N. (Box 67, Folder 17)
    - Organizations: Irish World (Box 67, Folder 18)
    - Organizations: Local Enterprise Development Unit [Belfast] (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - Organizations: Newry and Mourne Arts Centre (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - Organizations: Northern Ireland Tourist Board (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - Organizations: The Poetry Society [London] (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - Organizations: Public Record Office of Northern Ireland (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - Organizations: The Scottish Arts Council (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - Organizations: Ulster Museum Botanic Gardens Belfast (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - Organizations: Welsh Arts Council (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - Organizations: The Women's Centre [Belfast, Derry] (Box 68, Folder 9)
    - Organizations: Workers Educational Association: 1985-1988 (Box 68, Folder 10)
    - Organizations: Workers Educational Association: 1989-1991 (Box 68, Folder 11)
    - Organizations: Other organizations: 1971-1979 (Box 68, Folder 12)
    - Organizations: Other organizations: 1980-1983 (Box 68, Folder 13)
    - Organizations: Other organizations: 1984 (Box 68, Folder 14)
    - Organizations: Other organizations: 1985-1988 (Box 68, Folder 15)
    - Organizations: Other organizations: 1989 (Box 68, Folder 16)
    - Organizations: Other organizations: 1990-1991 (Box 68, Folder 17)
    - Organizations: Other organizations: undated (Box 68, Folder 18)
    - Educational Institutions: Cabin Hill School (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - Educational Institutions: Saint Patrick's Grammar School (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - Educational Institutions: Queen's University of Belfast: 1972-1983 (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - Educational Institutions: Queen's University of Belfast: 1984-1991 (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - Educational Institutions: Ulster Polytechnic (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - Educational Institutions: University College [Dublin] (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - Educational Institutions: University of Keele (Box 69, Folder 7)
    - Educational Institutions: University of Ulster (Box 69, Folder 8)
    - Educational Institutions: Other institutions (Box 69, Folder 9)
    - Libraries (Box 69, Folder 10)
    - Theatre Companies: Charabanc Theatre Company (Box 69, Folder 11)
    - Theatre Companies: Lyric Players Theatre (Box 69, Folder 12)
    - Theatre Companies: Pascal Theatre Company (Box 69, Folder 13)
    - Theatre Companies: Royal Court Theatre (Box 69, Folder 14)
    - Theatre Companies: Other companies (Box 69, Folder 15)
    - Individuals: 1969-1979 (Box 69, Folder 16)
    - Individuals: 1980 (Box 69, Folder 17)
    - Individuals: 1981 (Box 69, Folder 18)
    - Individuals: 1982 (Box 69, Folder 19)
    - Individuals: 1983 (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - Individuals: 1984 (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - Individuals: 1985 (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - Individuals: 1986-1987 (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - Individuals: 1988 (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - Individuals: 1989 (Box 70, Folder 6)
    - Individuals: 1990 (Box 70, Folder 7)
    - Individuals: 1991 (Box 70, Folder 8)
    - Individuals: undated (Box 70, Folder 9)
    - Traditional and Community Arts
    - 1972-1973 (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - January- July 1974 (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - August-December 1974 (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - January-March 1975 (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - April-June 1975 (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - July-December 1975 (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - January-May 1976 (Box 71, Folder 7)
    - June-December 1976 (Box 71, Folder 8)
    - 1977 (Box 71, Folder 9)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 71, Folder 10)
    - 1980-1985 (Box 71, Folder 11)
    - 1986-1987 (Box 71, Folder 12)
    - 1988 (Box 71, Folder 13)
    - 1989 (Box 71, Folder 14)
    - January-February 1990 (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - March-May 1990 (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - June-October 1990 (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - November-December 1990 (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - January-February 1991 (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - March 1991 (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - undated (Box 72, Folder 7)
  - Printed material, 1974-1991, Subseries 9.4; Box 73
    - ACNI Publications: 1988 (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - ACNI Publications: 1989 (Box 73, Folder 2)
    - ACNI Publications: 1990 (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - ACNI Publications: 1991 (Box 73, Folder 4)
    - ACNI Publications: undated (Box 73, Folder 5)
    - Clippings: 1974 - 1980 (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - Clippings: 1981 - 1987 (Box 73, Folder 7)
    - Clippings: 1988 - 1990 (Box 73, Folder 8)
    - Clippings: 1991 (Box 73, Folder 9)
    - Clippings: undated (Box 73, Folder 10)
    - British Council Publications (Box 73, Folder 11)
    - Assorted newsletters (Box 73, Folder 12)
    - Pamphlets and programs (Box 73, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 73, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 73, Folder 15)
  - Cultural Traditions Group materials, 1989-1994, Subseries 9.5; Box 74
    - Correspondence: 1989 (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: January - March 1990 (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: April - August 1990 (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: September - December 1990 (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: 1991 (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: 1992 (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: 1993 (Box 74, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: undated (Box 74, Folder 8)
    - Minutes and other official printed material: 1989 - 1990 (Box 74, Folder 9)
    - Minutes and other official printed material: 1990 - 1991 (Box 74, Folder 10)
    - Minutes and other official printed material: 1991 - 1992 (Box 74, Folder 11)
    - Minutes and other official printed material: 1992 - 1993 (Box 74, Folder 12)
    - Minutes and other official printed material: 1993 - 1994 (Box 74, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 74, Folder 14)
- Subject files, 1988-2000, Series 10; Boxes 75-77
  Series 10 groups together various printed materials which have an integrity as grouped entities. Such subject files tend to concern particular visits Michael Longley made to other countries, usually on reading tours; however other kinds of subject are represented here, such as the Charabanc Theatre Company, on which Michael Longley served as a member of the governing board, as well as a file for Seaman James Magennis, who inspired the poem "Ocean."
  - Visit to Canada, March 1988 (Canadian Association for Irish Studies) (Box 75, Folder 1)
  - Visit to Japan, 1991 (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - Thera Foundation seminar on poetry translation, Santorini, 1992 (Box 75, Folder 3)
  - Visit to USA, October 1992 (Box 75, Folder 4)
  - Trinity College, Dublin, 1993 Writing Fellow (Box 75, Folder 5)
  - Pushkin Prize, 1994 - 1995 (Box 75, Folder 6)
  - Visit to USA, February 1997 (Box 76, Folder 1)
  - Visit to Emory University, 1997, miscellaneous materials (Box 76, Folder 2)
  - Visit to Emory University, 1997, writing class materials and poems (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - Emory University correspondence 1995 - 2000 (Box 76, Folder 4)
  - Visit to USA, April - May 2000 (Box 76, Folder 5)
  - Seaman James J. Magennis [See also Subseries 2.1, The Weather in Japan, Ocean] (Box 76, Folder 6)
  - Charabanc Theatre Company (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - Department of Extra-Mural Studies handouts (Box 77, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous resumes, and recommendations written by Michael Longley (Box 77, Folder 3)
  - The Ireland Funds (Box 77, Folder 4)
  - The Ireland Funds, magazines (Box 77, Folder 5)
- Edna Longley papers, 1962-2000, Series 11; Boxes 78-80
  The Michael Longley collection contains a good deal of material by or about his wife, Edna Longley. Edna Longley is an eminent academic and critic who has taught for many years at Queen's University, Belfast. Collections of her criticism, including Poetry Between the Wars (1986), The Living Stream (1994) and Poetry and Posterity (2000), are some of the most important interventions in contemporary Irish poetry criticism. The series is divided into two distinct sections. The first contains materials more squarely concerning Edna Longley's academic life, including correspondence 1962-2000 and a number of drafts and typescripts of lectures and essays. The second contains materials concerning the John Hewitt Summer School (JHSS), and particularly documents regarding her acrimonious departure from the board of the JHSS in 1996.
  Organized into two subseries: (11.1) Edna Longley materials and (11.2) John Hewitt Summer School records.
  - Edna Longley materials, 1962-2000, Subseries 11.1; Box 78 - Box 80: folders 1-5
    - Correspondence, 1962 - 1969 (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1970 - 1979 (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1980 - 1984 (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1985 - 1986 (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1987 - 1989 (Box 78, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1990 - 1991 (Box 78, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1992 - 1993 (Box 78, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1994 (Box 78, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1995 (Box 78, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1996 (Box 78, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1997 - 1998 (Box 78, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1999 - 2000 (Box 78, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, undated (Box 78, Folder 13)
    - "Affliction (1): The Drama of Language and Form" (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - The Living Stream, "Introductory Essay" [draft] (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - The Living Stream, notes for launch speech (Box 79, Folder 3)
    - Review of The Bloodaxe Book of Contemporary Women Poets, Making for the Open, and Direct Dialing (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - Review of The Collected Works of Samuel Taylor Coleridge, ed. by David Erdman (Box 79, Folder 5)
    - Review of Compton Burnett's novels [See Subseries 2.1: Uncollected poems, "New Orleans" (Box -, Folder -)
    - Review of The Field Day Anthology, ed. Deane (Box 79, Folder 6)
    - Review of Flowers and Insects, by Ted Hughes (Box 79, Folder 7)
    - Review of Getting Through, by John McGahern (Box 79, Folder 8)
    - Review of Heathcliff and the Great Hunger by Terry Eagleton (Box 79, Folder 9)
    - Review of The Map of All My Youth, The Table Talk of W.H. Auden, Auden's Apologies for Poetry, and Collected Poems (Box 79, Folder 10)
    - Reviews of No Continuing City and Gorse Fires by Michael Longley (Box 79, Folder 11)
    - Review of Patrick Kavanagh: Born-Again Romantic by Antoinette Quinn (Box 79, Folder 12)
    - "The Rising, The Somme and Irish Memory" [2 copies] (Box 79, Folder 13)
    - "Speaking Volumes" [review of Escape from the Anthill by Hubert Butler] (Box 79, Folder 14)
    - "The Way Forward" (Box 79, Folder 15)
    - "Thomas, Philip Edward" and "Ledwidge, Francis Edward" [biographical entries] (Box 79, Folder 16)
    - [Untitled], Edna Longley in conversation with Jennifer Johnstone (Box 79, Folder 17)
    - Unidentified and incomplete drafts (Box 79, Folder 18)
    - Clippings of early reviews (Box 79, Folder 19)
    - Printed material (Box 79, Folder 20)
    - Lesson plans, syllabi, notes (Box 80, Folder 1)
    - Biographical materials (Box 80, Folder 2)
    - Mailing lists and addresses (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - Receipts and tickets (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 80, Folder 5)
  - John Hewitt Summer School records, circa 1966-1996, Subseries 11.2; Box 80
    - Correspondence, 1990 - 1995 (Box 80, Folder 6)